<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Álvaro Castellano - Personal Blog</title><link>https://a-castellano.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Álvaro Castellano - Personal Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 23:09:07 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://a-castellano.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying VM's using Cloud-init</title><link>https://a-castellano.github.io/posts/deploying-vms-using-cloudinit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 23:09:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://a-castellano.github.io/posts/deploying-vms-using-cloudinit/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-beginning---vm-templates">The beginning - VM templates&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Instead of having a server with multiple services installed, almost three years ago I started to use larger servers with KVM in order to manage multiple VM for those services. I had three &amp;ldquo;template&amp;rdquo; machines, for &lt;em>Debian 9&lt;/em>, &lt;em>Ubuntu 16.04&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Ubuntu 18.04&lt;/em>. Each time I needed a new machine I followed the following steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Clone the &amp;ldquo;template&amp;rdquo; VM.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Power on the new VM.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reconfigure network config and DNS&amp;rsquo;s in order to change VM network interface.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reboot the machine.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hope that I did not fail in any step.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Start working with the new VM.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>After 5-10 minutes my new VM was ready, great&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Restrict Linux users to certain workspaces</title><link>https://a-castellano.github.io/posts/restrict-linux-users-to-certain-workspaces-only/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 21:15:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://a-castellano.github.io/posts/restrict-linux-users-to-certain-workspaces-only/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this post I will talk about managing workspace access for certain users in Linux environments. We will set a workspace where some guests will be able to work in their amazing project. These users won&amp;rsquo;t have access to the files outside of their shared workspace. Finally we will use Linux ACL to manage user permissions inside their workspace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post resolves a real issue that I had few days ago. I was asked to restrict access to a couple users in a server. At the time I had no idea how to solve this issue in a smart way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My marvelous adventures with Docker - Part II</title><link>https://a-castellano.github.io/posts/my-marvelous-adventures-with-docker-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 21:24:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://a-castellano.github.io/posts/my-marvelous-adventures-with-docker-part-ii/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>In this post I continue my adventures with Docker. After creating our first image and container in the previous &lt;a href="https://a-castellano.github.io/posts/my-marvelous-adventures-with-docker-part-i/">post&lt;/a> I will look into how docker images can autostart services and how to establish communication between containers.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During this post we are creating images and storing them in Docker Hub. All my images are stored in my &lt;a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/acastellano/archonweb/">ArchonWeb&lt;/a> repository. All the scripts used in this post an be found in my &lt;a href="https://github.com/a-castellano/docker">Docker repo&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My marvelous adventures with Docker - Part I</title><link>https://a-castellano.github.io/posts/my-marvelous-adventures-with-docker-part-i/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 21:24:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://a-castellano.github.io/posts/my-marvelous-adventures-with-docker-part-i/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>In this post I talk about how to get started in Docker. First we will set a Docker server, afterwards we will create your first Docker image and we will run it.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s play with Docker and learn something about it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But wait, what is Docker? &lt;a href="https://www.docker.com">Docker&lt;/a> is an open platform to build, ship and run distributed applications anywhere. So you can run apps which &amp;ldquo;live&amp;rdquo; inside a contaniner runned and mannaged by Docker.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>